<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Recoverywork]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Recoverywork]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/recoverywork/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 09:09:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/recoverywork/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA["If even the DWP isn't Disability Confident, how will a million disabled people get jobs?"]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>"If even the DWP isn't Disability Confident, how will a million disabled people get jobs?"</h1><p>Bernadette Meaden of Ekklesia reveals the hypocrisy that lies within the current welfare-to-work system. She cites the example of an employee with a disability at the Department for Work and Pensions (DWP), who was dismissed after taking extended sick leave. This is particularly disheartening, as the DWP made a big splash in 2013 with its 'Disability Confident' campaign, in which the government "committed to halving the employment gap between disabled people and non-disabled people" (DWP, 2014). Meaden debunks the absurdity of the government's implications that people receiving ESA (only an additional £30 a week) have no incentive to find work, though arguably if people are to be treated this way by their so called Disability Confident employers, I would not blame them for not wanting to go back to work.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.ekklesia.co.uk/node/22614</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">800db309-edb9-44e5-aae3-e6a0d7dcaf10</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 08:49:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why don't people with mental health problems just get a job?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Why don't people with mental health problems just get a job?</h1><p>Charlotte Walker (@BipolarBlogger) Last week I went to the House of Lords, something I found quite intimidating. Thankfully I was supported by a member of Rethink campaigns team in giving oral evidence to a Parliamentary Review. Chaired by Lord Low of Dalston, the Review was set up to assess the likely impact of a proposed benefit cut.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/92ee78c6829cc9c183fc284886c28fa056a0bc3f.png"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://purplepersuasion.wordpress.com/2015/12/09/why-dont-people-with-mental-health-problems-just-get-a-job/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">827822c8-209b-40fa-a50b-f6f9885e54ef</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 09:06:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Creating a future beyond the Work Capability Assessment (WCA) (now with easy read version)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Creating a future beyond the Work Capability Assessment (WCA) (now with easy read version)</h1><p>Ekklesia is a Christian political think-tank committed to social justice. While I am mostly wary of religious organisations, Ekklesia's commitment to abolishing the Work Capability Assessment (WCA) is fascinating. The WCA is designed for individuals who are out of work due to disability and/or ill-health, to determine whether they are too ill to work. The WCA comprises a twenty page questionnaire that asks extremely intrusive questions about one's health and ability, such as: 'Can you chew and swallow food and drink without help or being prompted by another person?' In addition to this lengthy questionnaire, most people are also required to attend a medical assessment. These are heavy demands to place upon individuals that are unwell, so in my opinion any attempts to change the current system are welcome. Unfortunately, Ekklesia's method of data collection involves a fifteen page questionnaire, however as it is purely voluntary and does not involve the same strict time constraints as the WCA, it is perhaps more forgivable. It will be interesting to examine their results in due course.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://www.ekklesia.co.uk/node/22504</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">1d2ff36b-e206-4899-9d33-d77670856058</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 08:38:15 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>